Register of the Russia. Posol'stvo (France) Records, 1916-1924
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia, Posol'stvo (France) Records
1916-1924
26003
Hoover Institution Archives
37 manuscript boxes (15.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, and notes, relating to relations between France and the Russian Provisional Government, the Russian Revolution, counter-revolutionary movements, the Paris Peace Conference, and Russian emigres after the revolution. Entire collection also on microfilm (38 reels).
Russia. Posol'stvo (France)
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1926.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (38 reels).
Historical Note
The files of the Russian Embassy in Paris at the Hoover Institution cover the period of the ambassadorship of Basil Maklakoff. Maklakoff was appointed ambassador of the Russian Provisional Government to France by Alexander Kerensky in March 1917, and remained as the Russian ambassador until France recognized the U.S.S.R. in 1926. The bulk of the records is dated from 1918 until 1922 and document the operations of White Russian forces in their five-year struggle against the Bolsheviks. Activities of the Russian Embassy in Paris included participation in the Paris Peace Conference, 1919, and the organization of network of social welfare offices for the Russian immigrants, military and civilian, who fled Russia during the Russian Civil War.
The Hoover Institution also is in possession of the personal papers of Basil Maklakoff, 1917-1957, which document his activities after the recognition of the U.S.S.R. by France.
Diplomats and Officials Affiliated with the Russian Embassy in Paris, 1916-1924
Bakhmetev, Boris Aleksandrovich -
Russian Ambassador in Washington, D.C.
Baranovskii, A. -
Russian representative in Bucharest, Romania
Batchev, Mikhail Osipovich -
Agent of the Ministry of Commerce and Industry in France
Beliaev, M. -
Russian representative in Teheran, Persia
Benzenger, General -
Russian Military Representative in Constantinople, Turkey
Bonianovsky, M. -
Official in the Omsk Government Ministry of Finance
Botkin, Sergei D. -
Russian representative in Berlin, Germany
Braikovskii, Dimitrii Mikhailovich -
Russian Military representative in Vladivostok
Brant, Aleksandr -
Russian Military Agent in Berlin, Germany
Chaikovskii, N. V. -
President of the Provisional Northern Russian Government
Demidov, E. P. -
Russian Ambassador to Athens, Greece
Derber, P. -
President of the Council of Ministers of the Siberian Autonomous Government
Dmitriev, Vladimir Ivanovich -
Russian Military-Naval Attache in France
Emel'ianov, Ambassador -
Russian Ambassador to Bergen, Norway
Giers, Mikhail Nikolaevich -
Russian Ambassador to Rome, Italy
Golobachev, M. -
Minister of Foreign Affairs in the Omsk Government
Gorlov, Vladimir -
Russian Ambassador to Warsaw, Poland
Grimm, David D. -
Russian representative to Finland
Gul'kevich, M. -
Russian Ambassador to Stockholm, Sweden
Hildebrandt, M. -
Russian representative to Teheran, Persia
Iakimov, M. -
Russian Ambassador to Constantinople, Turkey
Iabukev, L. -
Chairman of the Assyrian National Council of Transcaucasia
Ignat'ev, General -
Russian Military Agent in France
Kandaurov, M. -
Military Attache in Stockholm, Sweden
Klemm, M. -
Advisor to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs for the Far East
Kliagin, Aleksandr Pavlovich -
Representative of the Ministry of Means of Communication in France.
Kliuchnikov, M. -
Assistant to the Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Omsk Government.
Kolesnikov, Vladimir Sergeevich -
Russian Military Representative in Vladivostok
Krupenskii, M. -
Russian Ambassador in Tokyo, Japan
Kudashev, N. A., Prince -
Russian Ambassador in Peking, China
Kutepov, M. -
Russian Representative in Warsaw, Poland
Lobachev, M. -
Russian Representative in Salonika.
Loris-Melikov, M. -
Russian envoy to Bangkok
Lysakovskii, A. -
Russian envoy to Rome (the Vatican)
Meiendorf, M. A., Baron -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in Copenhagen, Denmark
Merkulov, M. -
President of the Vladivostok Provisional Government
Nabokov, Konstantin Dmitrievich -
Russian Ambassador in London, England
Nelidov, Demitrii Aleksandrovich -
Russian Envoy to Brussels, Belgium
Neratov, Anatolii Anatloievich -
Chief of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs in Ekaterinodar and Russian Diplomatic Representative in Constantinople, Turkey
Okulitch, Joseph K. -
Plenipotentiary representative of the Priamur Government of Siberia in the U.S. and Manager of the Union of the Siberian Creamery Associations Abroad.
Oau, A. -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in Berne, Switzerland
Pelekhin, M. -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in Belgrade, Yugoslavia
Persiani, I. A. -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in Rome, Italy
Petriaev, A. M. -
Russian representative in Sofia, Bulgaria
Pilar, Baron -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in Oslo, Norway
Podshibiakin, M. -
Chairman of the Baku Russian National Council
Podtiagin, General M. P. -
Russian Military Attache in Tokyo, Japan
Poklevskii-Kozell', S. A. -
Russian Envoy to Bucharest, Romania
Popov, M. -
Russian Council in Harbin, China
Popov, E. -
Russian Council in Lisbon, Portugal
Pototskii, General -
Russian Military Attache in Copenhagen, Denmark
Preshbiano, Colonel -
Russian Military Agent in Brussels, Belgium
Protopopov, M. -
In charge of the Russian Consulate General in Marseilles, France
Pustoshkin, M. -
Russian Charge d'Affaires at the Hague
Rafal'skii, V. -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in Prague, Czechoslovakia
Rebinder, Count -
First Secretary at the Russian Mission in Belgium
Rodzianko, N. M. -
Chairman of the Provisional Committee of the All-Russian Zemskii Union, Ekaterinodar
Rosen, Baron -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in Norway
Sablin, Evgenii Vasil'evich -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in London, England
Serafimov, Boris Savvich -
Russian Charge d'Affaires in Constantinople, Turkey, and in Sofia, Bulgaria
Shcherbachev, Dmitrii Grigor'evich, General -
Russian Military Representative of Russian Armies to the Allied Governments and High Command
Shebeko, M. -
Russian representative in Helsingfors, Finland
Shcherbatskoy, M. -
Russian representative in Constantinople, Turkey
Shtrandtman, V. N. -
Russian Envoy to Belgrade, Yugoslavia
Smirnov, Aleksei -
Russian Envoy to Cairo, Egypt
Soldatenkov, M. -
Russian representative in London, England
Solov'ev, M. -
Russian Ambassador to Madrid, Spain
Stakhovich, M. -
Russian representative in Madrid, Spain
Struve, P. B. -
Head of the Russian Foreign Affairs Administration attached to the Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces in Southern Russia
Sukin, I. I. -
Russian Minister of Foreign Affairs, Omsk Government
Svechin, M. -
Russian representative at The Hague
Tatistchev, M. -
Director of the Ekaterinodar Diplomatic Administration
Tret'iakov, M. -
Minister of Foreign Affairs in Irkutsk
Trotskii-Seniutovich, Vladimir Nikolaevich -
Representative of General Iudenich
Ughet, Sergei Antonovich -
Russian Charge d'Affaires and Financial Attache at the Russian Embassy in Washington, D.C.
Ungern, Baron -
Russian Ambassador in Lisbon, Portugal
Viaz'mitinov, General V. -
Head of the General Staff of the Ekaterinodar Military Administration
Vasil'ev-Vasil'kov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich -
Russian Consul General in Algiers
Vinaver, Maksim Moiseevich -
Russian Minister of Foreign Affairs, Crimea
Volkonsky, Prince -
Russian Military Agent in Rome, Italy
Volkov, Admiral -
Russian military representative in London, England
Vologodskii, Petr Vasil'evich -
President of the Omsk Government Council of Ministers
Zamen, M. -
Russian representative in London, England
Zhukovskii, S. V. -
Russian representative at the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Omsk Government
Zubov, M. -
Vice President of the Provisional Northern Russian Government
Paris Peace Conference (1919-1920); France--Foreign relations--Russia.; France.; Refugees.; Russia--Foreign relations--France.; Russia.; Russians--France.; Siberia (Russia)--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Refugees.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union.; Ukraine--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Ukraine.; World War, 1914-1918--Peace.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.; World War, 1914-1918.
- MICROFILM REEL CONVERSION LIST
  Microfilm reel conversion list downloadable PDF file
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1917-1924 (Box 1-13)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence arranged by last name of correspondent
  - Abrikosov, Dimitri I., 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administration of Affairs of the Military Personnel and Prisoners of War (Paris), 1919 (Folder 2)
  - Administration of Foreign Supply to the Russian Armies (Paris), 1919-1921 (Folder 3)
  - Ageev, 1919 (Folder 4)
  - Aksakov, 1921 (Folder 5)
  - Alekseev, Aleksandr, 1918 (Folder 6)
  - All-Russian Union of Commerce and Industry (Yalta), 1918 (Folder 7)
  - American Red Cross (Paris), 1919 (Folder 8)
  - Antonov, Colonel, 1919 (Folder 9)
  - Artamonov, General, 1919-1920 (Folder 10)
  - Association Lumiere (Lille, France), 1919-1920 (Folder 11)
  - Bakh, 1918-1921 (Folder 12)
  - Bakhmetev, Boris Aleksandrovich
    - 1917-1920 (Folder 13-16)
    - 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baloff, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Banque Russe pour le Commerce Etranger (Paris), 1920 (Folder 3)
  - Baranovskii, A., 1919 (Folder 4)
  - Basily, Nicholas A., de, 1917 (Folder 5)
  - Batshev, Michael Osipovich, 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
  - Beliaev, M., 1919-1920 (Folder 7)
  - Belorussian Democratic Republic Delegation, 1919 (Folder 8)
  - Benzenger, General, 1919 (Folder 9)
  - Ber, P., 1919 (Folder 10)
  - Berkenheim, Aleksei, 1919 (Folder 11)
  - Bernatskii, Mikhail Vladimirovich, 1919-1920 (Folder 12)
  - Berthelot, M., 1918 (Folder 13)
  - Bicknell, Ernest P., Colonel, 1919 (Folder 14)
  - Bolelubsky, M., 1919 (Folder 15)
  - Bonianovsky, M., 1918 (Folder 16)
  - Botkin, Sergei, 1920-1921, 1923 (Folder 17)
  - Boyer, Paul, 1918 (Folder 18)
  - Boyer-Chammard, H., 1920 (Folder 19)
  - Braiskowskii, Dimitrii Mihailovich, 1921-1922 (Folder 20)
  - Brant, Aleksandr, 1919 (Folder 21)
  - Briand, Aristide, 1919 (Folder 22)
  - Brodrick, Lieutenant, 1919 (Folder 23)
  - Bureau of the Russian Press in Constantinople, 1920 (Folder 24)
  - Bystritskii, Vladimir P., Captain, 1919-1921 (Folder 25)
  - Carr, E. H., 1918-1919 (Folder 26)
  - Chaikovskii, N. V., 1920 (Folder 27)
  - Chambers, Mr., 1920 (Folder 28)
  - Chausson, M., 1922 (Folder 29)
  - Chelishchev, Viktor Nikolaevich, 1919 (Folder 30)
  - Chelnokov, M. V., 1919 (Folder 31)
  - Chernov, Victor Mikhailovich, 1921 (Folder 32)
  - Circulars, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Clermont-Tonnerre, Lieutenant, 1919 (Folder 2)
  - Commercial, Industrial and Financial Society for Russia (Paris), 1919-1920 (Folder 3)
  - Comptoir National d'Escompte de Paris, 1919-1920 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Universelle (Paris), 1920 (Folder 5)
  - Crowe, Eyre, Sir, 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Danish Legation in Paris, 1921-1922 (Folder 7)
  - Demidov, E. P., 1917-1923 (Folder 8-9)
  - Denikin, General, 1918-1919 (Folder 10)
  - Derber, P., 1918 (Folder 11)
  - Derby, Lord, 1918-1919 (Folder 12)
  - Dmitriev, Vladimir Ivanovich, 1918-1920 (Folder 13-14)
  - Dragomirov, General, 1919 (Folder 15)
  - Efremov, Ivan Nikolaevich, 1918, 1921-1922 (Folder 16)
  - Ekaterinodar War Minister, 1919 (Folder 17)
  - Elkin, Julius, 1919 (Folder 18)
  - Emel'ianov, Ambassador, 1918 (Folder 19)
  - Federov, Mikhail, 1919, 1923 (Folder 20)
  - France
    - Administration des Postes et Telegraphes, 1918 (Folder 21)
    - Ministry of Finance, 1920 (Folder 22)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1917-1919 (Folder 23)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1917-1919 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Frazier, Arthur Hugh, 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Gerasimov, Admiral, 1919 (Folder 7)
  - Giers, Mikhail Nikolaevich, 1917-1923 (Folder 8-10)
  - Golovin, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1919 (Folder 11)
  - Gordon, E., 1919 (Folder 12)
  - Gorlov, Vl., 1920-1921 (Folder 13)
  - Grimm, D. D., Professor, 1921-1922 (Folder 14)
  - Guins, Professor, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gul'kevich, M., 1917-1920 (Folder 2-5)
  - Hall-Patch, E. L., 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Hermonius, Eduard Karlovich, 1919-1920 (Folder 7)
  - Hildebrandt, M., 1920-1921 (Folder 8)
  - Iakimov, M., 1920 (Folder 9)
  - Iakubov, L., 1918-1919 (Folder 10)
  - Ignat'ev, General, 1918-1919 (Folder 11)
  - Iskul', Baron, 1917, 1919 (Folder 12)
  - Iudenich, General, 1919-1920 (Folder 13)
  - Kaminka, M., 1920 (Folder 14)
  - Kammerer, M., 1919-1920 (Folder 15)
  - Kandaurov, Colonel, 1919-1920 (Folder 16)
  - Kartashev, A., 1919 (Folder 17)
  - Kerensky, Alexander F., 1918 (Folder 18)
  - Kholmsen, I., General, 1922-1923 (Folder 19)
  - Khorvat, General, 1918 (Folder 20)
  - Klemm, M., 1918-1920 (Folder 21)
  - Kliagion, Aleksander Pavlovich, 1918-1919 (Folder 22)
  - Kliuchnikov, M., 1918 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Kloboukowski, Ministre, 1918 (Folder 2)
  - Kolchak, Admiral, 1919 (Folder 3)
  - Kolesnikov, Vladimir Sergeevich, 1921-1922 (Folder 4)
  - Krupenskii, M., 1917-1921 (Folder 5-6)
  - Kudashev, Prince N., 1917-1921 (Folder 7-8)
  - Kutepov, M., 1919-1920 (Folder 9)
  - Kuznetsov, Aleksandr Ivanovich, 1919 (Folder 10)
  - Laming, Richard, 1920 (Folder 11)
  - Latvia, Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Paris), 1919 (Folder 12)
  - League for the Regeneration of Russia (Lausanne), 1919 (Folder 13)
  - Lebedev, Vladimir, 1918 (Folder 14)
  - Lemoing, Robert, 1920 (Folder 15)
  - Leonovich, 1917 (Folder 16)
  - Leont'ev, M., 1919, 1921 (Folder 17)
  - Lianozov, Stepan Georgievich, 1919-1920 (Folder 18)
  - Lithuanian Delegation to the Peace Conference (Paris), 1919 (Folder 19)
  - Litvinoff, n.d. (Folder 20)
  - Lobachev, M., 1919 (Folder 21)
  - Logan, James, Colonel, 1919 (Folder 22)
  - Loris-Melikov, M., 1917 (Folder 23)
  - Lukomskii, A., General, 1919 (Folder 24)
  - L'vov, Prince Georgii Evgen'evich, 1918-1919 (Folder 25)
  - Lysakovskii, A., 1918-1923 (Folder 26)
  - Makalinskii, M., 1919 (Folder 27)
  - Makhrov, General, 1920 (Folder 28)
  - Malcolm, Ian, 1919 (Folder 29)
  - Markov, Dimitrii A., Dr., 1919 (Folder 30)
  - Marushkevskii, General, 1919 (Folder 31)
  - Maslov, Sergei Nikolaevich, 1919 (Folder 32)
  - Matsui, Keishiro, 1919-1920 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Mefodiev, 1919 (Folder 2)
  - Meinendorf, M. A., Baron, 1917-1921 (Folder 3)
  - Merkulov, M., 1921-1922 (Folder 4)
  - Mikhailov, M., 1919 (Folder 5)
  - Military-Historical and Statistics Committee (Paris), 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Miliukov, M., 1918 (Folder 7)
  - Miller, E. K., General, 1919-1920 (Folder 8-10)
  - Monkewitz, General, 1919 (Folder 11)
  - Morosoff, Ivan, 1920 (Folder 12)
  - Nabokov, Konstantin Dmitrievich, 1917-1919 (Folder 13-16)
  - Nabokov, Konstantin Dmitrievich, 1919-1922 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Nebiansky, M., 1923 (Folder 2)
  - Nelidov, Dmitrii Aleksandrovich, 1919-1920 (Folder 3)
  - Neratov, Anatolii Anatolievich, 1919-1924 (Folder 4-11)
  - Niessel, General, 1920 (Folder 12)
  - Nikiforov, 1919 (Folder 13)
  - Obshchee Delo (Paris), 1920 (Folder 14)
  - Okulitch, Joseph K., 1918-1922 (Folder 15)
  - Omsk Government
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1918-1919 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Ministry of the Navy, 1919 (Folder 4)
    - Ministry of Ways of Communication, 1919 (Folder 5)
    - War Ministry, 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Onu, A., 1917-1920 (Folder 7)
  - Ostrigradskii, 1919-1920 (Folder 8)
  - Paleologue, M., 1920 (Folder 9)
  - Palitsyn, Fedor Federovich, General, 1918-1919 (Folder 10)
  - Pantchoulidzeff, Alexis, 1918 (Folder 11)
  - Paris Commission of Supply for the Russian Armies, 1919 (Folder 12)
  - Pekekhin, M,., 1917-1920 (Folder 13)
  - Persiani, I. A., 1918-1922 (Folder 14)
  - Petriaev, A. M., 1921-1922 (Folder 15)
  - Pilar, Baron, 1917-1919 (Folder 16)
  - Plevako, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - Plushkevskii-Plushik, 1919 (Folder 18)
  - Podshibiakin, M., 1919 (Folder 19)
  - Podtiagin, M. P., General, 1920 (Folder 20)
  - Poguliaev, Sergei Sergeevich, Admiral, 1919-1920 (Folder 21)
  - Poincare, Lucien, 1919 (Folder 22)
  - Poklevskii-Kozell', S., 1919-1920 (Folder 23)
  - Polk, Frank L., 1919 (Folder 24)
  - Polovtsov, Aleksandr Aleksandrovich, 1920 (Folder 25)
  - Popov, E., 1917-1918 (Folder 26)
  - Popov, M., 1918 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Potoskii, General, 1919-1920 (Folder 2)
  - Prezhbiano, Colonel, 1919 (Folder 3)
  - Primorskii District Commercial-Industrial Board, 1922 (Folder 4)
  - Protopopov, M., 1917-1918, 1920-1922 (Folder 5)
  - Provisional Government of the Northern Region (Arkhangel'sk), 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Pusta, K. R., 1917-1918, 1921 (Folder 7)
  - Pustoshkin M., 1919 (Folder 8)
  - Rafalovich, Arthur G., 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
  - Rafal'skii, V., 1919-1921 (Folder 10)
  - Rebinder, Count, 1919 (Folder 11)
  - Regnault, M., 1919 (Folder 12)
  - Rodzianko, N. M., 1919 (Folder 13)
  - Romanovskii, Ivan Pavlovich, General, 1919 (Folder 14)
  - Rosen, Baron, 1920 (Folder 15)
  - Russian Bank of Commerce and Industry (Paris), 1919 (Folder 16)
  - Russian Consulate in Bordeaux, 1918-1919 (Folder 17)
  - Russian Consulate in Geneva, 1918-1919 (Folder 18)
  - Russian Consulate in Le Havre and Rouen, 1918 (Folder 19)
  - Russian Consulate in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 1920-1921 (Folder 20)
  - Russian Consulate in Kharbin, China, 1920 (Folder 21)
  - Russian Consulate General in Marseilles, France, 1917-1922 (Folder 22)
  - Russian Corporation, Limited, The (London) (Folder 23)
  - Russian Diplomatic Mission in Constantinople, 1920 (Folder 24)
  - Russian Merchant Marine Administration (Paris), 1919-1920 (Folder 25)
  - Russian Military Information Bureau in France, 1918 (Folder 26)
  - Russian Mission in Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1919 (Folder 27)
  - Russian Mission in Persia (Teheran), 1917-1920 (Folder 28)
  - Russian National Committee (Paris), 1922 (Folder 29)
  - Russian Public Committee in Estonia of Relief to the Starving (Revel), 1921 (Folder 30)
  - Russian Red Cross (Paris), 1921 (Folder 31)
  - Sablin, Evgenii Vasil'evich, 1917-1920 (Folder 32-33)
  - Sablin, Evgenii Vasil'evich, 1921-1923 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Sazonov, Sergei D., 1918-1920 (Folder 2)
  - Semenov, Ataman, 1921 (Folder 3)
  - Serafimov, Boris Savvich, 1919, 1923-1924 (Folder 4)
  - Sharp, William G., 1918-1920 (Folder 5)
  - Shaw, G. Howland, 1919 (Folder 6)
  - Shcherbachev, D. G., General, 1919-1920 (Folder 7-8)
  - Shcherbatskoy, M., 1919-1920 (Folder 9)
  - Shebeko, M., 1919 (Folder 10)
  - Shepkovskii, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1923 (Folder 11)
  - Shtrandtmann, V. N., 1917-1923 (Folder 12)
  - Shulgin, A., 1918-1919 (Folder 13)
  - Smirnov, Aleksei, 1918-1920 (Folder 14)
  - Soldatenkov, M., 1920 (Folder 15)
  - Solov'ev, M., 1917-1918 (Folder 16)
  - Spargo, John, 1921 (Folder 17)
  - Spears, E. L., Brigadier General, 1919-1920 (Folder 18)
  - Special Artillery Commission in France, Paris (Osobaia Artillerskaia Komissiia vo Frantsii), 1919 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Stakhovich, M., 1917-1918 (Folder 2)
  - Struve, P. B., 1919-1920 (Folder 3)
  - Sukin, M., 1919-1920 (Folder 4-6)
  - Svechin, Ataman Mikhail, 1919 (Folder 7)
  - Svechin, M., 1917-1918 (Folder 8)
  - Sychev, General, 1922 (Folder 9)
  - Tatishchev, M., 1919 (Folder 10)
  - Tchaikovsky, Nicholas W., 1918-1919 (Folder 11)
  - Tret'iakov, M., 1919-1920 (Folder 12)
  - Trotskii, 1917 (Folder 13)
  - Trotskii-Seniutovich, Valdimir Nikolaevich, 1919-1920 (Folder 14)
  - Troubetzkoy, Eugene, Prince, 1918-1920 (Folder 15)
  - Tsemovich, M., 1918 (Folder 16)
  - Ughet, Sergei Antonovich, 1918-1919, 1922-1923 (Folder 17)
  - Ukrainian National Committee (Paris), 1920 (Folder 18)
  - Ungern, Baron, 1917 (Folder 19)
  - Unified Committee of Russian Organizations of Relief to the Starving (Paris), 1921 (Folder 20)
  - Urquhart, Leslie, 1921 (Folder 21)
  - Vasil'ev-Vasil'kov, Aleksandr Konstantinovich, 1918-1920 (Folder 22)
  - Viaz'mitinov, V., General, 1919-1920 (Folder 23)
  - Vinaver, Maksio Mosieevich, 1919-1920 (Folder 24)
  - Volkonsky, Prince, 1919 (Folder 25)
  - Volkov, Admiral, 1918-1919 (Folder 26)
  - Vologodskii, Petr Vasil'evich, 1918-1919 (Folder 27)
  - Volunteer Army, Diplomatic Office at Ekaterinodar, 1919 (Folder 28)
  - Vostronin, M., 1918 (Folder 29)
  - Wallace, W. B., Colonel, 1919 (Folder 30)
  - Wedeniapine, M., 1918 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Weygand, General, 1919 (Folder 2)
  - Williams, 1918 (Folder 3)
  - Zamen, 1920 (Folder 4)
  - Zankevich, General, 1917 (Folder 5)
  - Zeidler, Professor, 1917 (Folder 6)
  - Zhukovskii, S. V., 1919-1920 (Folder 7)
  - Zubov, M., 1919 (Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 9-10)
  - Personal correspondence with various Russians consuls, 1921 (Folder 11)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1916-1924 (Box 13-36)
  Correspondence, notes, memoranda, charts, minutes of meetings, reports, bulletins, lists, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Alexeev Army, A history of (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - All-Cossack Economic Union (Folder 13)
  - All-Russian Constituent Assembly (Paris), 1921 (Folder 14)
  - All-Russian Patriotic Society (Folder 15)
  - All-Russian Union of Commerce and Industry (Folder 16)
  - American Relief Administration (Folder 17)
  - "Amis de la France" (Folder 18)
  - Austria-Hungary, Slavs in, ca. 1919 (Folder 19)
  - "Azbuka" (Odessa), February-March 1919 (Folder 20)
  - Baltic States
    - General (Folder 21)
    - General (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Baltic Information Office (Stockholm). Bulletins, 1918 (Folder 2)
    - Economy (Folder 3)
  - Belgium (Folder 4)
  - Benes, Eduard, opinion on the Russian question, 1921 (Folder 5)
  - Bernatskii, M. V., "The Problem of Restoration of Fiscal Distribution in Russia" (Problema Vozstanovleniia Denezhnago Obrashcheniia v Rossii), undated (Folder 6)
  - Bok, Captain B. I., report to the Diplomatic Conference in Paris, July 15, 1919 (Folder 7)
  - Brest-Litovsk Peace, 1918 (Folder 8)
  - British Technical Company of Siberia, trip to Russia, 1923 (Folder 9)
  - Bulgaria (Folder 10)
  - Bureau of the Russian press in Constantinople Bulletins, 1919-1921 (Folder 11)
  - Bystritskii, Captain (Folder 12)
  - Caucasus (Folder 13-14)
  - China
    - General, 1922 (Folder 15)
    - Relations with Russia, treaty violations, 1919 (Folder 16)
    - Russians in (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Chinese Eastern Railway, 1921 (Folder 2)
  - Commercial, Industrial and Financial Society for Russia (Paris) (Folder 3)
  - Commercial and financial matters (Folder 4)
  - Committee for the Organization of Food Relief to the Population of Liberated Areas of Russia, 1921 (Folder 5)
  - Committee of Representatives of the Judiciary Institutions in Harbin, March 1921 (Folder 6)
  - Communism in France, 1924 (Folder 7)
  - Communist International (Folder 8)
  - Conradi (Maurice) and Polounine (Aracius) trial in Lausanne, Switzerland, August 9, 1923 (Folder 9)
  - Crimea, economy, 1919 (Folder 10)
  - Czechoslovakia, relations with Russia, 1921 (Folder 11)
  - De Basily, Nicholas A. (Folder 12)
  - Denikin, General (Folder 13)
  - Denmark. Report from Copenhagen on Soviet Russia, 1923 (Folder 14)
  - Divorces among Jews (Folder 15)